vogella.com 2019-05-06

# Privacy Policy

Version 1.2 from 24.04.2018

vogella GmbH respects privacy and your rights to control your personal data. This Privacy Policy explains how vogella GmbH, here refered as we or us, collects, uses and shares your personal information in connection with your access to and use of the vogella Website www.vogella.com and Services. 

We do not and will not sell your data to third parties. Personal information is any information that can be used to identify you or that we can link to you. 

  1. Type of personal data collected by us
    1. Personal data provided by you
      * When using our Website, we collect the following personal information from you. We need this information in order to properly fulfill the contract between you and us and to comply with our legal obligations. Without this information, we may not be able to provide you access to our Website and Services.   
**Purchase of Services:**  
When you purchase a Service, (e.g. training, consulting, development, etc.) from our Website or through an Email or Fax, we collect information about your name, email address, address, communications and any information you choose to provide. We use this information in order to complete your purchase.   
**Communication with us and other users:**  
When you communicate with us, we collect information about your communications and any information you choose to provide. We use this information in order to provide you with a good customer support.   
**Additional data that you submit to us:**  
You may provide us with additional personal information. This additional data will be processed with your consent. You may decide to provide us with information, such as: e.g, if you complete a form or respond to surveys. We use this information in order to obtain a better user experience when using our Website and Services. 
    2. Personal data we collect automatically
We automatically collect information about you, to help analyse the usage of our Website and to display Advertising. Our Website uses third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit networkadvertising.org. 
      * Our Website uses Google products like Google AdSense, DoubleClick for Publishers and Google Analytics, services of Google Inc, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. ("Google"). This Google products use so-called Cookies. Cookies are Textfiles which are saved on the local computer to help analyse the usage of the Website. Information based on these cookies will be transferred to the servers of Google and saved on these servers. Through the usage of the Website you agree to the usage of this Google products. To see more information on how Google uses data when you use our Website, please visit this [site](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/). Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our Website.   
Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet.   
Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). 
      * We are participating in the affiliate program of Amazon.com, Inc., Amazon.com, Inc. P.O. Box 81226, Seattle, WA 98108-1226, USA and its subsidiaries. This affiliate program was created by Amazon to place advertisements and links to amazon Websites on external websites. We earn by advertising cost refunds. Amazon uses cookies to track the origin of orders. Amazon can therefore recognize that you have clicked on the partner link on our Website. For more information about Amazon's use of the data, please visit this [site](http://www.amazon.de/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=footer_privacy?ie=UTF8&nodeId=3312401).
      * Our website contains plugins from Facebook, 1601 South California Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA. Facebook is a social network. The respective plugin is recognizable by the Facebook logo or the "like me" button. You can view the complete overview of all plugins from Facebook at the following [link](http://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins)   
As soon as you visit our website, the Facebook plug-in establishes a direct connection between your Internet browser and the Facebook servers. In this way, Facebook is informed that our website has been visited with your IP address. In the event that you should be logged into Facebook, you can use the "Like" button to link the content on our website to your profile on Facebook. It is then possible for Facebook to associate your visit to our website with your Facebook account. We, as the provider of our website, are not informed by Facebook about the content of the transmitted data or the data usage. You can find more information under the following [link](http://de-de.facebook.com/policy.php)   
In the event that you should be a member of Facebook, but do not want Facebook to receive data about you via our website and connect it with your membership data, you must log out of Facebook before you visit our website. 
      * Our website contains features of Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom Street, Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA. If you use Twitter and especially the functions "Tweet or Re-Tweet", Twitter links your Twitter account with the websites you use. This will be announced to other users on Twitter, especially your followers. In this way, a data transfer to Twitter takes place.   
We, as the provider of our website, are not informed by Twitter about the content of the transmitted data or the data usage. For more information, visit the following [link](http://twitter.com/privacy)   
Please note, however, that you have the option to change your privacy settings on Twitter on your account settings at the following [link](http://twitter.com/account/settings).
  
Through the usage of this website you agree to the usage of cookies and the usage of your information to serve advertisement. 
  2. How we use the data we have received
We use the data we collect to provide you with access to our Website and offer you our Services, which includes using data to improve and personalize your experiences. We also use the data to communicate with you, e.g. to inform you about new services available, security and other types of updates. We use the data for the following purposes: 
    1. Provision of our Website
      * We use data to provide, operate, support and improve our Website and Services we offer to ensure that our users can use the our Website and Services as efficently as possible. This processing is necessary for the performance of our agreement we have with you. 
    2. Customer Support
      * We use data to respond to customer inquiries. This processing is necessary for the performance of our agreement we have with you, as well as to serve our legitimate interest. 
    3. Product improvement and development
      * We use data for research purposes and to develop and improve our Website and Services. Users can report issues on our Website. We use this data to improve and develop new fuctionalities of our Website or generate new Services. This processing is necessary to serve our legitimate interest. 
    4. Communication and Marketing
      * We use the data we collect to deliver and personalize our communications with you. For example, we may contact you by email to inform you about new Services on our Website, about updates of your purchased Services, to update you on a support issue or a reported issue, or to invite you to take part in a survey. This processing is necessary to serve our legitimate interest. 
    5. Security, Safety and Dispute Resolution
      * We use data to protect the security and safety of our Website, Services and our customers, to detect and prevent fraud, to resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. This processing is necessary to serve our legitimate interest. 
  3. How we may share personal data
We do not and will not sell your personal data. We only disclose your data as described in this Statement. We may share information with the following types of third parties. 
    1. Third party vendors
      * We use a variety of third-party vendors to carry out services like website hosting, online Service purchases and credit card processing. We only share your personal data as necessary, such as to complete a transaction or to provide a Service you have requested and only with vendors or agents working on our behalf for the purposes described in this Statement. In this case, your personal information will be shared with these agents or contractors but only for the purpose of performing services on behalf and under our instructions and in accordance with this Statement. It is our legitimate interest to share information with these parties for these purposes. 
    2. Sale or Merger
      * In the event of a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, we may share your personal information. In this case, we will notify you before your personal information is transferred and covered by another privacy policy 
    3. Compelled Disclosure
      * When legally required, strictly necessary for the performance of the services or to protect our rights, or the rights of our users, we disclose your personal information to law enforcement authorities, investigative organizations, our affiliates or in legal proceedings. 
    4. Aggregated data
      * We may also collect aggregated information (information about our users that we combine so that they no longer identify or refer to an individual user) and other anonymized regulatory compliance data, for industry and market analysis purposes, demographic profiling , marketing, advertising and other business purposes. 
  4. Security, storage and retention of collected personal data
    1. Security
      * We will take care of the security of your personal information. However, we cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat our security measures or use your personal information for improper purposes. You acknowledge that you provide your personal information at your own risk. 
    2. Storage
      * Your personal data collected by us may be stored and processed in any country where we or our service providers are located or maintain facilities. 
    3. Retention
      * We will retain your personal information for as long as we consider it necessary to enable you to use our Website and Services, to comply with applicable laws, resolve disputes with any parties and otherwise as necessary to allow us to conduct our business. All personal information we retain will be subject to this Privacy Policy. 
  5. Your Rights
In order to be in control of how your your personal data is used by us, the following actions are allowed to you: 
    * Request a copy of the personal data we hold about you.
    * Ask us to update your personal data for you. 
    * In certain situations, you can ask us to erase, block or restrict the personal information we hold about you, or object to particular ways in which we are using your personal information. 
    * In certain situations, you can also ask us to send the personal data you have given us to a third party.
Where we are using your personal data on the basis of your consent, you are entitled to withdraw that consent at any time. Moreover, where we process your personal information based on legitimate interest or the public interest, you have the right to object at any time to that use of your personal data. 
  6. Your Choices
You can, at any time, opt out to receive marketing communications about our Website and Services by sending us an Email to info@vogella.com. We respect your choice, and we will stop sending you promotional emails once you change your communication settings. 
  7. Changes to our Privacy Policy
    * We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time to reflect changes in our Website and Services. If we make changes to the Privacy Policy, we will post the amended Privacy Policy to our Website and update the "last update" date at the beginning of the Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with the amended Privacy Policy, please discontinue visiting our Website. If you continue using and accessing our Website after the date on which the amended Privacy Policy enters into force, your continued access to or use of our Website will be subject to the amended Privacy Policy. 
  8. How to contact us
    * If you have any questions or complaints about this Privacy Policy or our data handling procedures, you can contact us as follows:   
vogella GmbH, Haindaalwisch 17a, 22395 Hamburg, Germany.   
You can also contact us by e-mail at info@vogella.com.
